<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Tetrahedron]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib/media/favicon.png</url><title>Tetrahedron</title><link/></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:30:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 22:29:59 GMT</pubDate><copyright><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></copyright><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator>Nuvhandra</dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[QiZong]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>*A combination of QiGong with Yoga Asanas, constant movements focusing on State Movement Resonance*]]></description><link>movement/qizong.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">movement/QiZong.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 02:56:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[HayAgua]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Relacionado con: <a data-href="GeoWatch" href="projects/geowatch.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">GeoWatch</a><br><br><br><br><br>Los nodos hoja son dispositivos que contienen sensores y gestionan la comunicación con el entorno. Están diseñados para recolectar datos en tiempo real sobre las condiciones del suelo y el clima.<br><br>
<br>LoRaWAN: Utilizan tecnología LoRaWAN para comunicarse a larga distancia con el nodo rama o directamente con el backend.
<br>Manejo de Fallas:

<br>Detección de Fallas: Monitoreo continuo de la salud del sistema y notificación de fallas.
<br>Notificación: Envío de alertas al backend sobre problemas detectados.


<br>Validación de Datos:

<br>Filtrado de Datos: Aplicar reglas para validar los datos entrantes (ej., valores fuera de rango).
<br>Transformación: Convertir datos en bruto a un formato estructurado (JSON) antes de enviarlos al backend.


<br>Conversión de Datos: Transformar datos crudos a datos aplicables que puedan ser utilizados por el backend.
<br>Almacenamiento Local: Guardar datos temporalmente en caso de pérdida de conexión.
<br><br><br>Los nodos rama actúan como intermediarios entre los nodos hoja y el backend. Se encargan de recibir datos de múltiples nodos hoja y enviarlos al backend.<br><br>
<br>Cliente MQTT:

<br>Implementar un cliente MQTT que se conecte al broker MQTT del backend.
<br>Suscribirse a temas relevantes para recibir datos desde los nodos hoja.


<br>Validación de Comunicación:

<br>Asegurar que todos los nodos hoja están activos y comunicándose correctamente.


<br>Almacenamiento:

<br>Utilizar almacenamiento local (ej., base de datos SQLite) para guardar datos históricos y temporales.


<br>Conectividad:

<br>Soportar múltiples métodos de comunicación (4G LTE, Ethernet, LoRaWAN) para asegurar la conectividad continua.


<br><br><br>El backend es el núcleo del sistema, responsable del procesamiento de datos, la gestión de usuarios y la generación dinámica de contenedores según las necesidades del cliente.<br><br>
<br>
Generador de Contenedores:

<br>Utilizar Docker para crear contenedores basados en plantillas específicas para cada proyecto. Esto permite escalar fácilmente según las necesidades del cliente.
<br>Implementar un sistema que permita a los administradores definir configuraciones específicas mediante archivos YAML que describan la infraestructura requerida.


<br>
Broker MQTT:

<br>Configurar un broker MQTT (como Mosquitto) que gestione la comunicación entre todos los nodos. Debe ser capaz de manejar múltiples conexiones simultáneas y garantizar la entrega confiable de mensajes.


<br>
Limpieza de Datos para SQL:

<br>Implementar un módulo que procese los datos recibidos antes de almacenarlos en la base de datos SQL. Esto incluye validación, transformación y enriquecimiento de datos.


<br>
Manejador de Temas (Topic Handler):

<br>Diseñar un sistema que gestione diferentes temas MQTT, asegurando que los mensajes se dirijan correctamente a sus respectivos módulos dentro del backend.


<br>
Análisis y AI:

<br>Integrar algoritmos de machine learning para realizar análisis predictivos sobre el uso del agua y optimización del riego utilizando bibliotecas como Scikit-Learn o TensorFlow.


<br>
Manejo del Cliente:

<br>Gestionar las conexiones con clientes y dispositivos IoT, asegurando que todos estén correctamente autenticados y autorizados.


<br>
Análisis de Datos del Campo:

<br>Evaluar los datos recogidos por sensores utilizando herramientas como Pandas o GeoPandas para proporcionar información útil sobre el estado del riego.


<br>
Análisis de Datos Externos (3rd Party):

<br>Integrar servicios externos para obtener información adicional como imágenes satelitales o datos meteorológicos. Esto puede incluir APIs como OpenWeatherMap o Google Earth Engine.


<br><br><br>La interfaz del usuario debe ser intuitiva y accesible, mostrando información relevante sobre el riego y el estado del sistema.<br><br>
<br>
Interfaz Intuitiva:

<br>Diseñar un dashboard personalizable que permita a los usuarios ver información relevante a través de gráficos simples y mapas interactivos utilizando Streamlit o Leafmap.


<br>
Visualización Geoespacial:

<br>Integrar Leafmap o QGIS Web para mostrar mapas interactivos con información geoespacial sobre sensores y áreas irrigadas.


<br>
Conectividad en Tiempo Real:

<br>Utilizar WebSockets o MQTT para recibir actualizaciones automáticas sobre el estado del sistema en tiempo real.


<br>
Gestión de Usuarios y Roles:

<br>Implementar un sistema robusto para gestionar usuarios y roles, permitiendo diferentes niveles de acceso (administradores, agricultores, analistas).


<br><br><br>
<br>
API RESTful:

<br>Endpoints para gestión de usuarios, sensores, áreas, etc., utilizando Flask o FastAPI.


<br>
Base de Datos:

<br>PostgreSQL con PostGIS para almacenar información geoespacial.


<br>
MQTT Broker:

<br>Para manejar la comunicación entre dispositivos IoT.


<br>
Módulos de Análisis:

<br>Algoritmos para análisis predictivo y optimización del riego.


<br>
Configuración Modular:

<br>Usar YAML para definir configuraciones específicas por cliente.


<br><br>
<br>
Interfaz Intuitiva:

<br>Dashboard personalizable con visualizaciones claras utilizando Streamlit o frameworks como React/Vue.js.


<br>
Visualización Geoespacial:

<br>Integración con Leafmap o QGIS Web para visualización geoespacial interactiva.


<br>
Conectividad en Tiempo Real:

<br>Actualizaciones automáticas utilizando WebSockets o MQTT.


<br>
Gestión de Usuarios y Roles:

<br>Control sobre quién puede ver o modificar qué datos.


<br><br>Para asegurar una comunicación rápida y confiable entre todos los componentes, se recomienda establecer un protocolo ligero utilizando MQTT. Aquí tienes algunas sugerencias:<br>
<br>
Estructura Clara para Temas:
irrigation/{client_id}/{node_type}/{sensor_id}/data
irrigation/{client_id}/{node_type}/{sensor_id}/status
irrigation/{client_id}/commands
irrigation/{client_id}/alerts


<br>
Calidad del Servicio (QoS):<br>
Utilizar QoS nivel 1 o nivel 2 para asegurar que los mensajes sean entregados al menos una vez o exactamente una vez respectivamente.

<br>
Retención de Mensajes:<br>
Habilitar la retención en mensajes críticos donde sea necesario mantener el último estado conocido.

<br>
Seguridad:<br>
Implementar autenticación mediante usuario/contraseña o certificados SSL/TLS para asegurar la comunicación entre nodos y el broker MQTT.

<br>
Validación Rápida de Comunicación:<br>
Implementar un mecanismo simple donde cada nodo envíe un mensaje “heartbeat” a intervalos regulares para validar su conexión al broker.

<br><br>nodes:
  leaf_nodes:
    - node_id: "leaf_node_01"
      sensors:
        humidity_sensor:
          type: "humidity"
          id: "sensor_001"
        temperature_sensor:
          type: "temperature"
          id: "sensor_002"
      communication:
        type: "LoRaWAN"
        fault_handling: true
        data_validation: true
        local_storage_enabled: true
      storage_path: "/local/storage/path"

  branch_nodes:
    - node_id: "branch_node_01"
      mqtt_client_id: "mqtt_client_01"
      communication_methods:
        primary: "4GLTE"
        secondary: "Ethernet"
      data_storage_path: "/branch/storage/path"

backend:
  container_generator:
    template_algorithm: "custom_template_algorithm"
    data_cleaning_enabled: true
    mqtt_broker_url: "mqtt://broker_url"
    topic_handler_enabled: true
    ai_analysis_enabled: true
    field_data_analysis_enabled: true
    third_party_data_analysis_enabled: true
    satellite_image_integration_enabled: true

frontend:
  dashboard_configurable_elements:
    real_time_values_displayed: true
    summary_reports_enabled: true
    user_roles_management_enabled: true
    device_status_monitoring_enabled: true
    map_visualization_enabled: true
    irrigation_estimation_displayed: true
]]></description><link>projects/hayagua/hayagua.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/HayAgua/HayAgua.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:10:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Requerimientos del Sistema]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br><br>
<br>
Sensores:

<br>GET /api/sensors: Obtener la lista de todos los sensores.
<br>GET /api/sensors/{sensor_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un sensor.
<br>POST /api/sensors: Crear un nuevo sensor.
<br>PUT /api/sensors/{sensor_id}: Actualizar información de un sensor existente.
<br>DELETE /api/sensors/{sensor_id}: Eliminar un sensor.


<br>
Nodos Hoja:

<br>GET /api/leaf-nodes: Obtener la lista de todos los nodos hoja.
<br>GET /api/leaf-nodes/{node_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un nodo hoja.
<br>POST /api/leaf-nodes: Crear un nuevo nodo hoja.
<br>PUT /api/leaf-nodes/{node_id}: Actualizar información de un nodo hoja existente.
<br>DELETE /api/leaf-nodes/{node_id}: Eliminar un nodo hoja.


<br>
Nodos Rama:

<br>GET /api/branch-nodes: Obtener la lista de todos los nodos rama.
<br>GET /api/branch-nodes/{node_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un nodo rama.
<br>POST /api/branch-nodes: Crear un nuevo nodo rama.
<br>PUT /api/branch-nodes/{node_id}: Actualizar información de un nodo rama existente.
<br>DELETE /api/branch-nodes/{node_id}: Eliminar un nodo rama.


<br>
Datos de Riego:

<br>GET /api/watering-data: Obtener datos históricos y en tiempo real sobre el riego.
<br>POST /api/watering-data: Enviar datos nuevos sobre el riego desde sensores.


<br>
Usuarios:

<br>GET /api/users: Obtener la lista de todos los usuarios.
<br>GET /api/users/{user_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un usuario.
<br>POST /api/users: Crear un nuevo usuario.
<br>PUT /api/users/{user_id}: Actualizar información de un usuario existente.
<br>DELETE /api/users/{user_id}: Eliminar un usuario.


<br><br>
<br>Implementar autenticación mediante JWT (JSON Web Tokens) para asegurar que solo los usuarios autorizados puedan acceder a ciertos endpoints.
<br>Definir roles de usuario (administrador, agricultor, analista) con permisos específicos.
<br><br>
<br>Utilizar PostgreSQL con PostGIS para almacenar datos geoespaciales y permitir análisis avanzados.
<br><br>
<br>Implementar MQTT para la comunicación en tiempo real entre dispositivos IoT, nodos hoja y el backend.
<br><br><br>
<br>La API debe ser capaz de manejar al menos X solicitudes por segundo sin degradar el rendimiento.
<br><br>
<br>La arquitectura debe permitir la adición fácil de nuevos nodos y sensores sin necesidad de reconfiguración significativa.
<br><br>
<br>Todos los datos sensibles deben ser cifrados durante la transmisión y almacenamiento.
<br><br>
<br>La interfaz del usuario debe ser intuitiva y fácil de usar, especialmente para usuarios no técnicos.
<br><br>
<br>Backend: Python (Flask o FastAPI), PostgreSQL con PostGIS, MQTT (Mosquitto).
<br>Frontend: Streamlit para prototipos rápidos o React/Vue.js para aplicaciones más complejas.
<br>Contenedores: Docker para contenerizar la aplicación; Kubernetes para orquestar los contenedores.
<br>Visualización Geoespacial: Leafmap o QGIS Web para mostrar mapas interactivos.
<br><br><br><br>
<br>Administrador
<br>Agricultor
<br><br>El agricultor necesita monitorear las condiciones del suelo en su campo y ajustar el sistema de riego basado en datos en tiempo real proporcionados por los sensores instalados. El administrador configura el sistema y gestiona los usuarios y dispositivos.<br><br>
<br>
Autenticación del Usuario

<br>El agricultor inicia sesión en la aplicación utilizando sus credenciales.
<br>El sistema valida las credenciales y proporciona acceso al dashboard.


<br>
Visualización del Dashboard

<br>El agricultor accede al dashboard donde se muestran datos en tiempo real sobre humedad del suelo, temperatura y estado del sistema de riego.
<br>Se visualizan mapas interactivos que muestran la ubicación de los sensores en el campo utilizando Leafmap o QGIS Web.


<br>
Monitoreo de Sensores

<br>El agricultor puede ver el estado actual de cada sensor (activo/inactivo).
<br>Se reciben alertas en caso de que algún sensor detecte condiciones críticas (ej., baja humedad).


<br>
Ajuste del Sistema de Riego?

<br>Basado en los datos visualizados, el agricultor puede ajustar manualmente el sistema de riego a través del dashboard o programar riegos automáticos basados en condiciones específicas definidas previamente.


<br>
Análisis Histórico

<br>El agricultor puede acceder a datos históricos para analizar patrones en la humedad del suelo y optimizar el uso del agua a lo largo del tiempo.


<br>
Configuración por Parte del Administrador

<br>El administrador puede agregar nuevos sensores o nodos al sistema utilizando una interfaz dedicada.
<br>Puede gestionar roles y permisos para diferentes usuarios, asegurando que cada uno tenga acceso solo a las funciones necesarias.


<br>
Integración con Datos Externos

<br>Se pueden integrar datos meteorológicos externos para mejorar las decisiones sobre el riego utilizando APIs externas (ej., OpenWeatherMap).


]]></description><link>projects/hayagua/requerimientos-del-sistema.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/HayAgua/Requerimientos del Sistema.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:31:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[RESTful API]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Los recursos son las entidades que tu API manejará. En el contexto de tu plataforma, los recursos principales pueden incluir:<br>
<br>Sensores: Información sobre cada sensor (tipo, ubicación, estado).
<br>Nodos Hoja: Dispositivos que contienen sensores y gestionan la comunicación.
<br>Nodos Rama: Intermediarios que gestionan la comunicación entre nodos hoja y el backend.
<br>Datos de Riego: Datos históricos y en tiempo real sobre el riego.
<br>Usuarios: Información sobre los usuarios del sistema y sus roles.
<br><br>A continuación se presentan ejemplos de cómo podrían estructurarse los endpoints para cada recurso:<br><br>
<br>GET /api/sensors: Obtener la lista de todos los sensores.
<br>GET /api/sensors/{sensor_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un sensor.
<br>POST /api/sensors: Crear un nuevo sensor.
<br>PUT /api/sensors/{sensor_id}: Actualizar información de un sensor existente.
<br>DELETE /api/sensors/{sensor_id}: Eliminar un sensor.
<br><br>
<br>GET /api/leaf-nodes: Obtener la lista de todos los nodos hoja.
<br>GET /api/leaf-nodes/{node_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un nodo hoja.
<br>POST /api/leaf-nodes: Crear un nuevo nodo hoja.
<br>PUT /api/leaf-nodes/{node_id}: Actualizar información de un nodo hoja existente.
<br>DELETE /api/leaf-nodes/{node_id}: Eliminar un nodo hoja.
<br><br>
<br>GET /api/branch-nodes: Obtener la lista de todos los nodos rama.
<br>GET /api/branch-nodes/{node_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un nodo rama.
<br>POST /api/branch-nodes: Crear un nuevo nodo rama.
<br>PUT /api/branch-nodes/{node_id}: Actualizar información de un nodo rama existente.
<br>DELETE /api/branch-nodes/{node_id}: Eliminar un nodo rama.
<br><br>
<br>GET /api/watering-data: Obtener datos históricos y en tiempo real sobre el riego.
<br>POST /api/watering-data: Enviar datos nuevos sobre el riego desde sensores.
<br><br>
<br>GET /api/users: Obtener la lista de todos los usuarios.
<br>GET /api/users/{user_id}: Obtener información específica sobre un usuario.
<br>POST /api/users: Crear un nuevo usuario.
<br>PUT /api/users/{user_id}: Actualizar información de un usuario existente.
<br>DELETE /api/users/{user_id}: Eliminar un usuario.
<br><br>Los métodos HTTP que utilizarás son:<br>
<br>GET: Para recuperar datos del servidor (ej., obtener sensores).
<br>POST: Para enviar datos al servidor y crear nuevos recursos (ej., crear un nuevo sensor).
<br>PUT: Para actualizar recursos existentes (ej., actualizar información de un sensor).
<br>DELETE: Para eliminar recursos (ej., eliminar un sensor).
<br><br>El cuerpo del mensaje será necesario principalmente para las solicitudes POST y PUT. Aquí hay ejemplos de cómo podría verse el cuerpo para crear o actualizar recursos:<br><br>{
    "sensor_id": "sensor_001",
    "type": "humidity",
    "location": {
        "lat": 40.7681,
        "lon": -73.9817
    },
    "status": "active"
}
<br><br>{
    "type": "humidity",
    "status": "inactive"
}
<br><br>Implementa autenticación utilizando JWT (JSON Web Tokens) o OAuth2 para asegurar que solo los usuarios autorizados puedan acceder a ciertos endpoints. Esto es crucial para proteger datos sensibles y controlar el acceso basado en roles.<br><br>Aquí tienes un ejemplo completo de cómo podría lucir la definición del endpoint para obtener todos los sensores:<br>GET /api/sensors

Response:
HTTP/1.1 200 OK
Content-Type: application/json

[
    {
        "sensor_id": "sensor_001",
        "type": "humidity",
        "location": {
            "lat": 40.7681,
            "lon": -73.9817
        },
        "status": "active"
    },
    {
        "sensor_id": "sensor_002",
        "type": "temperature",
        "location": {
            "lat": 40.7682,
            "lon": -73.9818
        },
        "status": "active"
    }
]
<br><br>Es importante documentar tu API utilizando herramientas como Swagger o Postman para que otros desarrolladores puedan entender cómo interactuar con ella. La documentación debe incluir:<br>
<br>Descripción general de la API.
<br>Listado completo de endpoints con ejemplos.
<br>Detalles sobre autenticación y autorización.
<br>Ejemplos de solicitudes y respuestas.
]]></description><link>projects/hayagua/restful-api.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/HayAgua/RESTful API.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 05:25:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[FarmBox]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Creating a superfood that is rich in protein, vitamins, amino acids, and contains psilocybin (the psychoactive compound found in certain mushrooms) can be achieved through the cultivation of mycelium, larvae, and microbes. This manual outlines the processes involved in growing these organisms, focusing on mycelium as a primary source due to its nutritional benefits and potential for sustainable food production.<br><br><br>Mycelium is the vegetative part of fungi, consisting of a network of filaments called hyphae. It plays a crucial role in nutrient cycling and can be cultivated for its high protein content and other nutritional benefits. Mycelium can grow rapidly on various substrates, making it an ideal candidate for sustainable food production[1][2].<br><br>Mycelium is rich in:<br>
<br>Protein: Contains 30-45% protein content.
<br>Amino Acids: Provides essential amino acids, though it may be low in methionine[1][5].
<br>Vitamins: Particularly B vitamins which are crucial for human health[1][2].
<br>Fiber: The glucans in cell walls contribute to dietary fiber[1].
<br><br><br>
<br>Materials: Use organic waste materials such as straw, coffee grounds, or agricultural by-products.
<br>Preparation: Pasteurize the substrate to eliminate competing microorganisms. This can be done by steaming or using hot water.
<br><br>
<br>Introduce mycelium spores (spawn) into the prepared substrate. Common species include Agaricus bisporus (button mushroom) and Pleurotus ostreatus (oyster mushroom)[3].
<br><br>
<br>Maintain optimal conditions (temperature: 20-25°C; humidity: 60-70%) for mycelium growth.
<br>Monitor for contamination and ensure adequate air exchange.
<br><br>After approximately 2-4 weeks, once the substrate is fully colonized by mycelium:<br>
<br>Cut the substrate into manageable pieces.
<br>Dry the harvested mycelium to enhance shelf life and concentrate nutrients.
<br><br><br>To include psilocybin, select species such as Psilocybe cubensis or Psilocybe semilanceata. These species can be cultivated similarly to other mushrooms but require specific conditions to maximize psilocybin content.<br><br>
<br>Follow similar substrate preparation and inoculation steps as with non-psychoactive mycelium.
<br>Ensure controlled conditions that favor psilocybin production, typically through specific light cycles and nutrient availability.
<br><br><br>Consider using larvae (e.g., black soldier fly larvae) as an additional protein source:<br>
<br>Feed organic waste to larvae in a controlled environment.
<br>Harvest larvae after several weeks for high-protein biomass.
<br><br>Utilize microbial fermentation to enhance nutritional profiles:<br>
<br>Employ bacteria or yeast such as Saccharomyces cerevisiae or Lactobacillus species.
<br>These microbes can produce additional proteins and vitamins during fermentation processes.
<br><br>Combining mycelium with larvae and microbial sources creates a superfood that is:<br>
<br>High in protein and essential amino acids.
<br>Rich in vitamins and minerals.
<br>Sustainable due to low resource requirements for cultivation.
<br>Citations:<br>
[1] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9863462/" target="_blank">https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9863462/</a><br>
[2] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jafc.3c03307" target="_blank">https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jafc.3c03307</a><br>
[3] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://academic.oup.com/jambio/article/134/1/lxac018/6908764?login=false" target="_blank">https://academic.oup.com/jambio/article/134/1/lxac018/6908764?login=false</a><br>
[4] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://eatableadventures.com/news/mycelium-the-super-ingredient-of-the-food-industry/" target="_blank">https://eatableadventures.com/news/mycelium-the-super-ingredient-of-the-food-industry/</a><br>
[5] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.mdpi.com/2076-2607/10/7/1379" target="_blank">https://www.mdpi.com/2076-2607/10/7/1379</a><br>
[6] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0958166922000635" target="_blank">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0958166922000635</a><br>
[7] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/270496538_Utilization_of_the_nutrients_in_the_soluble_and_insoluble_fractions_of_fungal_mycelium_by_larvae_of_the_stag_beetle_Dorcus_rectus_Coleoptera_Lucanidae" target="_blank">https://www.researchgate.net/publication/270496538_Utilization_of_the_nutrients_in_the_soluble_and_insoluble_fractions_of_fungal_mycelium_by_larvae_of_the_stag_beetle_Dorcus_rectus_Coleoptera_Lucanidae</a><br>
[8] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2665927124001928" target="_blank">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2665927124001928</a><br><br><br>Petridish culture:<br>
<br>Mushroom

<br>Cordycepts
<br>Lions Maine


<br>Yeast
<br>Bacteria
<br>Iron
<br>Zinc
<br>Magnesium
<br>Fat Acids
<br>Biotin
<br>Vitamins A-Z
<br>Omega 3
<br>Antioxidants
<br>Methionine: essential amino acid
<br><br><br>
<br>Power Box

<br>12 V (2 plugs)
<br>5 V (USB)
<br>3.3 V


<br>Temperature

<br>powerbox heat ventilator(steerling )


<br>Ventilation

<br>Fan with filters, optimum 2 sides


<br>Humidifier
<br>Sensors

<br>CO2
<br>temperature
<br>humidity


]]></description><link>projects/farmbox.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/FarmBox.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 23:40:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[GeoWatch]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Interface for location, monitoring and controlling devices<br>Your Docker Compose architecture is designed to facilitate a constant data flow from sensor devices (like ESP32) to a backend system, where data is processed and stored in a PostgreSQL/PostGIS database. The following outlines the key components and their interactions based on your provided configuration:<br><br><br>
<br>Function: These devices act as data sources, sending their schema and sensor data via MQTT.
<br>Data Flow:

<br>Schema sent to: /box/boxname/schema
<br>Sensor data sent to: /box/boxname/data


<br><br>
<br>Service: mqtt
<br>Image: eclipse-mosquitto
<br>Role: Acts as the messaging hub for receiving data from sensors and distributing it to the backend service.
<br>Ports: Exposes port 1883 for MQTT communication.
<br><br>
<br>Service: backend
<br>Build Context: Located in ./backend
<br>Role: 

<br>Subscribes to MQTT topics to receive sensor data.
<br>Processes and saves this data into the PostgreSQL database.


<br>Environment Variables:

<br>Configured with MQTT broker details and database credentials.


<br><br>
<br>Service: db
<br>Image: postgis/postgis
<br>Role: 

<br>Stores geospatial data and sensor readings.
<br>Allows for advanced queries on spatial data.


<br>Volumes: Persists data in a defined volume.
<br><br>
<br>Service: grafana
<br>Image: grafana/grafana
<br>Role: Visualizes the data stored in PostgreSQL.
<br>Ports: Exposes port 3000 for web access.
<br>Plugins Installed: Includes various plugins for enhanced visualization capabilities.
<br><br>
<br>Service: streamlit
<br>Build Context: Located in ./frontend
<br>Role: Provides an interactive web application for displaying device locations and statistics.
<br>Ports: Exposes port 8501 for user access.
<br><br>[ESP32 Sensors] --(MQTT)--&gt; [MQTT Broker] --(Data)--&gt; [Backend]
         |                          |                      |
         |                          |                      |
         +-------------------------&gt;+                      |
                                 (Schema)                |
                                                       [PostgreSQL]
                                                         |
                                                         |
                                                      [Grafana]
                                                         |
                                                      [Streamlit]
<br><br>
<br>Real-time Data Processing: The architecture allows for immediate processing of incoming sensor data through the backend service.
<br>Geospatial Capabilities: Using PostGIS enables advanced geospatial queries, making it suitable for applications in precision agriculture and environmental monitoring.
<br>Visualization Tools: Grafana and Streamlit provide robust platforms for visualizing and interacting with the collected data.
<br><br>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://randomnerdtutorials.com/esp32-mqtt-publish-subscribe-arduino-ide/" target="_blank">https://randomnerdtutorials.com/esp32-mqtt-publish-subscribe-arduino-ide/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://community.home-assistant.io/t/connecting-long-range-sensors-using-lora-and-mqtt/584230" target="_blank">https://community.home-assistant.io/t/connecting-long-range-sensors-using-lora-and-mqtt/584230</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://hackaday.com/2022/12/26/connecting-commercial-433-mhz-sensors-to-mqtt-and-home-assistant-with-rtl-sdr/" target="_blank">https://hackaday.com/2022/12/26/connecting-commercial-433-mhz-sensors-to-mqtt-and-home-assistant-with-rtl-sdr/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://blog.streamlit.io/how-to-build-a-real-time-live-dashboard-with-streamlit/" target="_blank">https://blog.streamlit.io/how-to-build-a-real-time-live-dashboard-with-streamlit/</a>
<br>
]]></description><link>projects/geowatch.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/GeoWatch.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 17:24:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[MIDIFOX]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 Error:SyntaxError: Unexpected token 'C', "C
#include"... is not valid JSONSyntaxError: Unexpected token 'C', "C
#include"... is not valid JSON
    at JSON.parse (&lt;anonymous&gt;)
    at AB (plugin:obsidian-kanban:63:25595)
    at R_ (plugin:obsidian-kanban:63:26895)
    at yf.mdToBoard (plugin:obsidian-kanban:67:322)
    at vf.getParsedBoard (plugin:obsidian-kanban:67:5782)
    at vf.newBoard (plugin:obsidian-kanban:67:2204)
    at vf.registerView (plugin:obsidian-kanban:67:1837)]]></description><link>projects/midifox.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/MIDIFOX.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:45:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Powerbox]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Recycle of PC Power Source as a Bench Power Source for circuit testing and different ranges of Voltage]]></description><link>projects/powerbox.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/Powerbox.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 15:48:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[ProjectsCanva]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 TerraNavis5<a aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__lane-settings-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>Design frame<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>Design mold<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>freecad design<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>list of materials<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>prototype<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>+ Add a cardMethane digester2<a aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__lane-settings-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>design<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>list of materials<a data-ignore-drag="true" aria-label="More options" class="kanban-plugin__item-postfix-button clickable-icon"><span data-icon="lucide-more-vertical" class="kanban-plugin__icon "><svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" width="24" height="24" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2" stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round" class="svg-icon lucide-more-vertical"><circle cx="12" cy="12" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="5" r="1"></circle><circle cx="12" cy="19" r="1"></circle></svg></span></a>+ Add a card]]></description><link>projects/projectscanva.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/ProjectsCanva.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 19:59:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Protein Farm]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="exoworkpsy.jpg" src="projects/assets/exoworkpsy.jpg"><br>A semi automated ecosystem farm capable of breeding Tenebrionidae larva.<br>
<br>The mentioned larva can be used for human consumption
<br><br>
<br>Tenebrionidae

<br>Zophobas morio
<br>Molitor
<br>Obscurus
<br>Bolitotherus cornutus

<br>Feed on <a data-href="Ganoderma applanatum" href="research/fungi/ganoderma-applanatum.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Ganoderma applanatum</a>




<br>
<br><br>
<br>Beauveria bassiana
<br><br>
<br>Cabbage
<br>Potato
<br>Wheat bran
<br>Rice bran (whole and defatted)
<br>Corn dry distillers' grain
<br>Spent brewery dry grain
<br>Canola meal
<br>Sunflower meal
<br><br><img alt="amanitaindustry.jpg" src="projects/assets/amanitaindustry.jpg"><br><img alt="amanitabeet.jpg" src="projects/assets/amanitabeet.jpg"><br><br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.crodeon.com/blogs/news/professionally-farming-mealworms" target="_blank">https://www.crodeon.com/blogs/news/professionally-farming-mealworms</a>]]></description><link>projects/protein-farm.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/Protein Farm.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 23:46:01 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/assets/exoworkpsy.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/assets/exoworkpsy.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[RF Pulse Distance Measurement System Using ESP8266 and RTL-SDR]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a class="tag" href="?query=tag:electronics" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#electronics</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:programming" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#programming</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:research" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#research</a> 
 <br><a href=".?query=tag:electronics" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#electronics</a> <a href=".?query=tag:programming" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#programming</a> <a href=".?query=tag:research" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#research</a> <br><br>This project aims to create a simple RF-based distance measurement system using an ESP8266 microcontroller to generate PWM pulses, an FM transmitter built with two 2N3904 transistors, and an RTL-SDR receiver to capture the transmitted signals. The system will measure the time taken for a signal to travel to a reflective surface and back, allowing for distance calculations based on the time-of-flight principle.<br><br><br>
<br>ESP8266 Module (e.g., NodeMCU or Wemos D1 Mini)
<br>FM Transmitter Circuit:

<br>Two 2N3904 NPN transistors
<br>Resistors (e.g., 10kΩ)
<br>Capacitors (e.g., 10nF)
<br>Inductor (optional for tuning)


<br>RTL-SDR Receiver: USB SDR receiver for signal processing.
<br>Custom Antennas: For both the transmitter and receiver.
<br>Power Supply: Suitable for the components (e.g., USB power bank).
<br>Wires and Connectors: For connections between components.
<br>Breadboard or PCB: For assembling the circuit.
<br>Computer with SDR Software: To process received signals.
<br><br>
<br>Arduino IDE: For programming the ESP8266.
<br>SDR Software: Such as SDR# (SDRSharp) or GQRX for signal analysis.
<br><br><br><br>The FM transmitter circuit will use two 2N3904 transistors to create a simple oscillator and amplifier configuration.<br>
<br>
Schematic Diagram:
+Vcc
  |
  R1
  |
  |-------| 
  |       | 
 C1      C2
  |       |
 ---     ---
 | |     | |
 ---     ---
  |       |
----      ----
|  |      |  |
|  |      |  |
----      ----
 T1       T2
(2N3904) (2N3904)
  |       |
 Antenna  |
          GND


<br>
Component Values:

<br>R1: 10kΩ resistor
<br>C1, C2: 10nF capacitors
<br>T1, T2: NPN transistors (2N3904)
<br>Antenna: A simple dipole antenna tuned to your desired frequency.


<br><br>
<br>Connect the components on a breadboard according to the schematic.
<br>Ensure proper connections for power supply and ground.
<br><br><br>
<br>Download and install Arduino IDE from the official website.
<br><br>
<br>Open Arduino IDE, go to File &gt; Preferences, and add this URL to "Additional Board Manager URLs":
http://arduino.esp8266.com/stable/package_esp8266com_index.json


<br>Go to Tools &gt; Board &gt; Board Manager, search for "ESP8266", and install it.
<br><br>
<br>Use a USB-to-serial converter to connect the ESP8266 to your computer.
<br>Select the appropriate board (NodeMCU or similar) from Tools &gt; Board.
<br><br><br>The following code generates PWM pulses on a specified pin connected to the base of the FM transmitter:<br>const int pwmPin = D1; // Pin connected to FM transmitter base
const int pulseDuration = 100; // Pulse duration in milliseconds

void setup() {
    pinMode(pwmPin, OUTPUT);
}

void loop() {
    // Send pulse
    analogWrite(pwmPin, 255); // Full duty cycle
    delay(pulseDuration);
    analogWrite(pwmPin, 0); // Turn off pulse
    delay(1000); // Wait before sending next pulse
}
<br><br><br>
<br>Plug your RTL-SDR receiver into a USB port on your computer.
<br><br>
<br>Download software like SDR# (SDRSharp) or GQRX to process received signals.
<br><br>
<br>Set up your software to tune into the frequency used by your FM transmitter (e.g., around 100 MHz).
<br>Use a custom antenna designed for optimal reception at your chosen frequency.
<br><br><br>When you send a pulse from the ESP8266, start a timer immediately.<br><br>Use SDR software to monitor when the pulse is received.<br><br>Use the formula:<br>
where:<br>
<br> = Time taken for the signal to return.
<br> = Speed of light (approximately  m/s).
<br><br>import time
import numpy as np
from rtlsdr import RtlSdr

sdr = RtlSdr()

# Configure SDR parameters
sdr.sample_rate = 2.048e6 # Sample rate in Hz
sdr.center_freq = 100e6 # Set this to your transmitter frequency in Hz
sdr.gain = 'auto'

# Start receiving samples
print("Starting reception...")

start_time = time.time()

# Read samples and check for pulse (this is simplified)
samples = sdr.read_samples(256*1024)

# Process samples here (detect pulse)
# This could involve analyzing FFT or other methods

end_time = time.time()

# Calculate round-trip time in seconds
round_trip_time = end_time - start_time

# Calculate distance in meters
distance = (round_trip_time * 299792458) / 2 

print(f"Distance measured: {distance} meters")

sdr.close()
<br><br><br>Verify that your RF pulses are being transmitted correctly by monitoring them with SDR software.<br><br>Ensure accurate timing by comparing against known distances.<br><br>Use both RF distance measurements and any additional data from accelerometers if desired for enhanced accuracy.<br><br>This project outlines how to create an RF Pulse Distance Measurement System using an ESP8266, an FM transmitter built with two NPN transistors, and an RTL-SDR receiver. By following these steps, you can build a functional system capable of measuring distances based on time-of-flight principles using RF signals.<br>If you have any specific questions regarding components, wiring diagrams, or programming examples, feel free to ask!]]></description><link>projects/rf-pulse-distance-measurement-system-using-esp8266-and-rtl-sdr.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/RF Pulse Distance Measurement System Using ESP8266 and RTL-SDR.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:48:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Temple of the Sun]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a class="tag" href="?query=tag:plants" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#plants</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:nature" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#nature</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:biology" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#biology</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:ecology" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#ecology</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:energy" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#energy</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:projects" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#projects</a> <a class="tag" href="?query=tag:research" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#research</a> 
 <br><a href=".?query=tag:plants" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#plants</a> <a href=".?query=tag:nature" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#nature</a> <a href=".?query=tag:biology" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#biology</a> <a href=".?query=tag:ecology" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#ecology</a> <a href=".?query=tag:energy" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#energy</a> <a href=".?query=tag:projects" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#projects</a> <a href=".?query=tag:research" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#research</a><br>
A location which presents all resources needed to live a sustainable life, focusing on knowledge and the preservation of life<br><br><br><br><br>]]></description><link>projects/temple-of-the-sun.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/Temple of the Sun.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:50:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[terrain light sound action]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>**<br>
<img alt="SCH_Schematic1_1-P1_2024-12-05.svg" src="projects/assets/sch_schematic1_1-p1_2024-12-05.svg"><br><br>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://forum.arduino.cc/t/transistor-gain-and-loudspeaker/167131/8" target="_blank">https://forum.arduino.cc/t/transistor-gain-and-loudspeaker/167131/8</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://learn.adafruit.com/adafruit-audio-fx-sound-board?view=all" target="_blank">https://learn.adafruit.com/adafruit-audio-fx-sound-board?view=all</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://gist.github.com/stonehippo/308a5f5c49d4981ac976" target="_blank">https://gist.github.com/stonehippo/308a5f5c49d4981ac976</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://learn.adafruit.com/adafruit-audio-fx-sound-board/serial-audio-control" target="_blank">https://learn.adafruit.com/adafruit-audio-fx-sound-board/serial-audio-control</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://docs.arduino.cc/built-in-examples/sensors/ADXL3xx/" target="_blank">https://docs.arduino.cc/built-in-examples/sensors/ADXL3xx/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://howtomechatronics.com/tutorials/arduino/how-to-track-orientation-with-arduino-and-adxl345-accelerometer/" target="_blank">https://howtomechatronics.com/tutorials/arduino/how-to-track-orientation-with-arduino-and-adxl345-accelerometer/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.instructables.com/Accelerometer-Controlled-LEDs/" target="_blank">https://www.instructables.com/Accelerometer-Controlled-LEDs/</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://rotering-net.de/tut/arduino/led-mit-transistor-steuern.html" target="_blank">https://rotering-net.de/tut/arduino/led-mit-transistor-steuern.html</a>
<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.murata.com/products/sound/library/basic/circuit" target="_blank">https://www.murata.com/products/sound/library/basic/circuit</a>
]]></description><link>projects/terrain-light-sound-action.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/terrain light sound action.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:58:26 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/assets/sch_schematic1_1-p1_2024-12-05.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/assets/sch_schematic1_1-p1_2024-12-05.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Glitz Rock]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Pinche trabajo 
a mi me gusta el relajo

Este Burocracia
es una simple falacia

A mi me gusta bailar
me gusta cantar
me gusta correr
no me digas que hacer

Atrapado yo en esta ideologia perversa
que envenena con placeres mi cabeza
]]></description><link>writings/glitz-rock.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">writings/Glitz Rock.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 16:29:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Intro]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="histilus_sumer3.svg" src="assets/histilus_sumer3.svg"><br><br>Welcome to a journey of exploration, creativity, and self-discovery. This book are my ideas, projects, drawings, thoughts, and learning – a reflection of my multifaceted interests and passions. At its core, this work aims to enrich the reader with knowledge that fosters revolution and independence, enabling a harmonious coexistence with technology and the environment. It is a call to embrace a world without borders, where self-sustaining communities thrive on the free exchange of knowledge, living in harmony with the natural world. As an individual with a deep appreciation for art, music, engineering, technology, sciences, and philosophy, I strive to weave these diverse threads into a cohesive narrative. This book is not merely a collection of words and images; it is a window into my experiences, my life, and my vision for a better world. Through these pages, you will embark on a journey that transcends boundaries, challenging conventional thinking and inspiring a new paradigm of living. We will delve into the realms of art, exploring its power to evoke emotions and provoke thought. We will venture into the depths of science and technology, unraveling their potential to revolutionize our understanding of the world and our place within it. Moreover, this book is a testament to the belief that knowledge should be freely shared, empowering individuals and communities to forge their own paths towards self-sufficiency and harmony with the natural world. It is a call to action, inviting readers to embrace their curiosity, question the status quo, and actively participate in shaping a future where innovation and sustainability go hand in hand.<br><br><img alt="doodle_serpent2.svg" src="assets/doodle_serpent2.svg"><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br><br>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoNfVL3YH5pNd3NqRDI2rIw" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCoNfVL3YH5pNd3NqRDI2rIw" target="_blank">Youtube</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.twitch.tv/nuvhandra" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.twitch.tv/nuvhandra" target="_blank">Twitch</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://github.com/k3ll3x" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://github.com/k3ll3x" target="_blank">Github</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://soundcloud.com/kellex_urps" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://soundcloud.com/kellex_urps" target="_blank">Fred Kelder Soundcloud</a>
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://soundcloud.com/user-99991795" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://soundcloud.com/user-99991795" target="_blank">Nuvhandra Soundcloud</a>
<br><a data-href="Donate" href="donate.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Donate</a>
<br>]]></description><link>index.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">INDEX.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 20:29:36 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="assets/histilus_sumer3.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="assets/histilus_sumer3.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Services]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a class="tag" href="?query=tag:services" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#services</a> 
 <br><a href=".?query=tag:services" class="tag" target="_blank" rel="noopener nofollow">#services</a> <br><br>
<br>Environmental Monitoring: Develop smart systems using Raspberry Pi and Arduino for real-time environmental data tracking.
<br>Geospatial Analysis: Perform spatial data analysis and visualization with QGIS to support ecological research.
<br><br>
<br>Custom Solutions: Create tailored applications in Python, C/C++, and JavaScript to meet specific needs.
<br>API Development: Build robust APIs for seamless data integration and enhanced web functionalities.
<br><br>
<br>Insight Extraction: Analyze complex datasets with Pandas and Matplotlib to derive actionable insights.
<br>Interactive Dashboards: Design dashboards to visualize key metrics and performance indicators.
<br><br>
<br>Responsive Applications: Develop user-friendly web applications optimized for performance.
<br>Full-Stack Solutions: Enhance web applications with back-end development expertise.
<br><br>
<br>Content Creation: Write technical articles and guides on programming, Earth sciences, and technology trends.
<br>Educational Resources: Develop materials that simplify complex scientific concepts for broader audiences.
<br><br>
<br>Hands-On Workshops: Conduct sessions on QGIS, Python programming, and environmental monitoring technologies.
<br>Consultation Services: Provide one-on-one consultations for tech implementation in projects.
<br><br><br><br><br> I can adapt to any project :)]]></description><link>services.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Services.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 23:50:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[5 Buddhist Tibetan Rites]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="doodle_tibetanrites.svg" src="lib/media/doodle_tibetanrites.svg"><br>
Constant movement in each exercise<br>
<br>Spin with extended arms
<br>Lay down and move your legs upwards while moving chin to chest
<br>Sit down on your knees, arms in hips and stretch forward
<br>Sit down and shift your hips up and forwards
<br>Seal pose to down facing dog
<br>Meditate]]></description><link>movement/5-buddhist-tibetan-rites.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">movement/5 Buddhist Tibetan Rites.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 23:29:46 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="lib/media/doodle_tibetanrites.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="lib/media/doodle_tibetanrites.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[MusikSack]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="layout-blueprint_v2.svg" src="projects/assets/layout-blueprint_v2.svg"><br>Abstract<br>A Single-board computer with a micro-controller for processing Analog and Digital inputs, designed for music production, computer graphics, and other open-source projects.<br>Design<br>
<br>
Single-board computer (Raspberry Pi, Orange Pi, …)

<br>
Audio Card

<br>Display
<br>Micro-controller (Arduino, Teensy, ESP32, …)

<br>Analog Inputs
<br>Digital Inputs




<br>
USB (female ports)

<br>
Power Source ~5V (Battery, direct connection with transformer)

<br><img alt="musicsackconcept.png" src="projects/assets/musicsackconcept.png"><br>Circuit Desing for Micro-controller Analog &amp; Digital Inputs<br><img alt="musiksackschematic.png" src="projects/assets/musiksackschematic.png"><br>Single-board Computer Software<br>For processing every Input and Output (I/O) several drivers and software have to be prepared and loaded into the computer. I will start with the process of recieveing data from the micro-controller (Arduino) via the Serial port at a fast baud rate.<br>Reading and Writing to Serial Port<br>source: <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://gist.github.com/jerome-labidurie/5dde0ec105fe88aaf5fa8f3c54f4b07d" target="_blank">https://gist.github.com/jerome-labidurie/5dde0ec105fe88aaf5fa8f3c54f4b07d</a><br>Or maybe using Boost library?<br>Boost<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_66_0/doc/html/boost_asio/reference/serial_port.html" target="_blank">https://www.boost.org/doc/libs/1_66_0/doc/html/boost_asio/reference/serial_port.html</a><br>OpenCL<br>Open Computing Language, cross-platform, parallel programming.<br>Juce<br>Multi-platform audio application framework.<br><br>//reading analog inputs from motors as rotary encoder

//2 tiny motor helicopter &amp; 2 yellow plates motor &amp; motor no plate
Serial.println(map(analogRead(A0), 510, 520, 0, 4));

//solar motor also yellow plate
Serial.println(map(analogRead(A0), 510, 520, -1, 4));
Copy<br>use std::time::Duration;

fn main() {
    println!("Serial Reader");
    let baud_rate = 9600;
    //let ports = serialport::available_ports().expect("No ports found!");
    let mut port = serialport::new("/dev/ttyUSB0", baud_rate)
        .timeout(Duration::from_millis(10))
        .open().expect("Failed to open port");
    loop {
        let mut serial_buf: Vec&lt;u8&gt; = vec![0; 32];
        if let Ok(_ret) = port.read(serial_buf.as_mut_slice()) {
            for i in serial_buf {
                println!("{}", i);
            }
        }
    }
}
Copy]]></description><link>projects/musiksack.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/MusikSack.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 15:21:20 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/assets/layout-blueprint_v2.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/assets/layout-blueprint_v2.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mycelium Box]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>To grow oyster mushrooms using calcium oxide for pasteurization, follow this detailed manual. This method involves preparing the substrate, pasteurizing it with a high-pH lime bath, inoculating with mushroom spawn, and creating the right conditions for fruiting.<br><br><br>
<br>Oyster Mushroom Spawn: Obtain high-quality spawn from a reputable supplier.
<br>Substrate: Common substrates include straw, sawdust, or coffee grounds.
<br>Calcium Oxide (Lime): Used for creating a high-pH environment for pasteurization.
<br>Water: For soaking and mixing.
<br>Containers or Bags: For holding the substrate during incubation and fruiting.
<br>Thermometer: To monitor temperature.
<br>Spray Bottle: For misting during fruiting.
<br><br><br>Choose a suitable substrate. Straw is commonly used due to its availability and nutrient content.<br><br>
<br>Chop the Straw: Cut the straw into small pieces (about 1-3 inches long) to increase surface area.
<br>Soak in Water: Soak the chopped straw in water for several hours or overnight to hydrate it.
<br><br><br>
<br>
Prepare Lime Bath:

<br>Mix calcium oxide with water to create a high-pH solution. A typical ratio is about 1 cup of calcium oxide per gallon of water.
<br>Ensure the solution is well-mixed.


<br>
Pasteurize the Substrate:

<br>Submerge the soaked straw in the lime solution for 12-18 hours. This process raises the pH of the substrate, helping to kill off unwanted microorganisms while allowing beneficial fungi to thrive.
<br>After soaking, drain the straw and rinse it thoroughly with clean water to remove excess lime.


<br><br>
<br>
Mix Spawn with Substrate:

<br>In a clean environment, mix the hydrated and pasteurized straw with oyster mushroom spawn at a rate of about 5-10% spawn by weight.
<br>Ensure even distribution of spawn throughout the substrate.


<br>
Fill Containers:

<br>Pack the inoculated substrate into clean containers or plastic bags. Leave some space at the top for air exchange.


<br>
Seal Containers:

<br>If using bags, seal them with a breathable filter patch or make small holes for gas exchange.


<br><br>
<br>
Create Ideal Conditions:

<br>Place the filled containers in a dark, warm location (20-24°C or 68-75°F) with high humidity (around 80%).
<br>Monitor for signs of contamination; healthy mycelium should appear white and fluffy.


<br>
Wait for Colonization:

<br>Allow 2-3 weeks for the mycelium to fully colonize the substrate. The substrate should turn completely white.


<br><br>
<br>
Initiate Fruiting:

<br>Once fully colonized, move the containers to a well-lit area with indirect sunlight.
<br>Cut slits or holes in the bags or containers to allow mushrooms to grow out.


<br>
Maintain Humidity and Fresh Air:

<br>Mist the substrate twice a day to maintain humidity levels around 70-80%.
<br>Ensure good air circulation to prevent mold growth.


<br>
Temperature Control:

<br>Keep temperatures within an optimal range (12-18°C or 54-64°F) during fruiting.


<br><br>
<br>
Timing:

<br>Mushrooms are ready to harvest when their caps begin to uncurl and lighten in color (usually within 5-10 days after initiating fruiting).


<br>
Harvest Method:

<br>Use clean hands or a knife to gently twist or cut mushrooms at their base without damaging surrounding mycelium.


<br><br>
<br>
Flushes:

<br>After harvesting, soak the substrate in water overnight to rehydrate and encourage additional flushes of mushrooms.
<br>Repeat misting and care as before; expect multiple flushes over several weeks.


<br>
Composting:

<br>After all flushes are complete, consider composting the spent substrate as it can enrich garden soil.


<br>Citations:<br>
[1] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://fatmoonmushrooms.com/pages/oyster-grow-kit-instructions" target="_blank">https://fatmoonmushrooms.com/pages/oyster-grow-kit-instructions</a><br>
[2] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://grocycle.com/how-to-grow-oyster-mushrooms/" target="_blank">https://grocycle.com/how-to-grow-oyster-mushrooms/</a><br>
[3] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.mushroom-corner.com/posts/how-to-grow-oyster-mushrooms-at-home" target="_blank">https://www.mushroom-corner.com/posts/how-to-grow-oyster-mushrooms-at-home</a><br>
[4] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.wildabundance.net/blog/how-to-grow-mushrooms-on-logs/" target="_blank">https://www.wildabundance.net/blog/how-to-grow-mushrooms-on-logs/</a><br>
[5] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.pilzbrut.de/media/image/storage/opc/Anleitungen/anleitung_2_austern-limonenpilze_fertigkultur_11-21_englisch.pdf" target="_blank">https://www.pilzbrut.de/media/image/storage/opc/Anleitungen/anleitung_2_austern-limonenpilze_fertigkultur_11-21_englisch.pdf</a><br>
[6] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://verticalveg.org.uk/blog/91251-how-to-grow-oyster-mushrooms-at-home" target="_blank">https://verticalveg.org.uk/blog/91251-how-to-grow-oyster-mushrooms-at-home</a><br>
[7] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://site.extension.uga.edu/newtonextanr/files/2023/05/Oyster-mushroom-Growing-Instructions-1.pdf" target="_blank">https://site.extension.uga.edu/newtonextanr/files/2023/05/Oyster-mushroom-Growing-Instructions-1.pdf</a><br>
[8] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.instructables.com/1-How-to-Grow-Oyster-Mushrooms-Low-Tech/" target="_blank">https://www.instructables.com/1-How-to-Grow-Oyster-Mushrooms-Low-Tech/</a><br><br><br>Based on the information from the provided sources, some easy-to-grow edible fungi that contain antioxidants, vitamins, zinc, copper, selenium,<br>
lutein, zeaxanthin, fatty acids, magnesium, protein are:<br>Cordyceps, Lion's Mane, and Shiitake<br>
<br>
Agaricus bisporus (Button Mushrooms):

<br>Contains minerals like zinc and copper[1][5].
<br>Rich in antioxidants and vitamins like B vitamins (B2, B3, folate, B5)[5].


<br>
Pleurotus ostreatus (Oyster Mushrooms):

<br>Contains antioxidants and minerals like selenium[1][5].
<br>Provides protein and essential nutrients[5].


<br>
Lentinula edodes (Shiitake Mushrooms):

<br>Rich in antioxidants like lutein and zeaxanthin[1].
<br>Contains essential fatty acids and minerals like zinc and copper[1].


<br>
Cordyceps militaris:

<br>Contains selenium and phenolic compounds with antioxidant properties[4].
<br>Provides protein and other bioactive compounds beneficial for health[4].


<br>These edible fungi are relatively easy to grow and can be cultivated at home or in controlled environments. They offer a range of health<br>
benefits due to their antioxidant content, essential minerals, vitamins, and other nutrients that support overall well-being.<br>Citations:<br>
[1] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.mdpi.com/2072-6643/15/8/1913" target="_blank">https://www.mdpi.com/2072-6643/15/8/1913</a><br>
[2] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6331815/" target="_blank">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6331815/</a><br>
[3] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00217-020-03646-1" target="_blank">https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00217-020-03646-1</a><br>
[4] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8622900/" target="_blank">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8622900/</a><br>
[5] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/food-features/mushrooms/" target="_blank">https://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/food-features/mushrooms/</a><br><br><a data-href="Protein Farm" href="projects/protein-farm.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener nofollow">Protein Farm</a><br>Based on the information from the provided sources, to enhance the diet that includes fungi and Tenebrio molitor larvae, you could consider adding the following components for a more balanced and nutritious diet:<br>
<br>
Variety of Vegetables and Fruits:

<br>Including a diverse range of vegetables and fruits can provide essential vitamins, minerals, and antioxidants that complement the nutrients from fungi and Tenebrio molitor larvae[4].


<br>
Whole Grains:

<br>Incorporating whole grains like quinoa, brown rice, and oats can add fiber, complex carbohydrates, and additional nutrients to the diet[4].


<br>
Healthy Fats:

<br>Adding sources of healthy fats such as avocados, nuts, seeds, and olive oil can contribute to overall health and provide essential fatty acids[4].


<br>
Legumes:

<br>Legumes like lentils, chickpeas, and beans are rich in protein, fiber, and various vitamins and minerals that can complement the protein content from Tenebrio molitor larvae[4].


<br>
Dairy or Plant-Based Alternatives:

<br>Including dairy products or plant-based alternatives like soy milk or almond milk can provide calcium, vitamin D, and protein for overall nutritional balance[4].


<br>By incorporating a variety of nutrient-dense foods like vegetables, fruits, whole grains, healthy fats, legumes, and dairy or plant-based alternatives alongside fungi and Tenebrio molitor larvae in your diet, you can ensure a more well-rounded and complete nutritional profile that supports overall health and well-being.<br>Citations:<br>
[1] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.researchgate.net/figure/Nutritional-value-of-conventional-meat-and-yellow-mealworm-Tenebrio-molitor-on-a-fresh_tbl1_342254365" target="_blank">https://www.researchgate.net/figure/Nutritional-value-of-conventional-meat-and-yellow-mealworm-Tenebrio-molitor-on-a-fresh_tbl1_342254365</a><br>
[2] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.mdpi.com/2075-4450/14/4/359" target="_blank">https://www.mdpi.com/2075-4450/14/4/359</a><br>
[3] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.mdpi.com/2304-8158/12/22/4092" target="_blank">https://www.mdpi.com/2304-8158/12/22/4092</a><br>
[4] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://jasbsci.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40104-023-00945-x" target="_blank">https://jasbsci.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s40104-023-00945-x</a><br>
[5] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0100112" target="_blank">https://journals.plos.org/plosone/article?id=10.1371%2Fjournal.pone.0100112</a>]]></description><link>projects/mycelium-box.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/Mycelium Box.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 20:18:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Solaris Odyssey]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>A platform provides unique, off-grid travel opportunities.<br>Goal is to provide travelers with a truly self-sustainable, off-grid accommodation and travel experience that minimizes environmental impact while fostering cultural exchange and personal growth. The platform could appeal to eco-conscious, adventurous travelers seeking unique, transformative journeys.<br>
<br>Eco-friendly, solar-powered yurts or tiny homes equipped with organic gardens, water harvesting systems, and renewable energy generators.
<br>Opportunities for guests to learn sustainable living skills like permaculture, composting, and renewable energy.
<br>Partnerships with local communities to provide authentic cultural experiences and support the local economy.
<br>Carbon-neutral transportation options like electric vehicles or hot air balloons.
<br>Curated itineraries and trip planning services focused on immersive, low-impact travel experiences.
<br><br><img alt="flyingyurt.png" src="projects/assets/flyingyurt.png"><br>]]></description><link>projects/solaris-odyssey.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/Solaris Odyssey.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 18:48:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/assets/flyingyurt.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/assets/flyingyurt.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Terra Navis]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>	Who am I?
	
	Across the seas, I roam and sail,  
	In a vessel long, with dragon's tail.  
	Self-sustaining, this Viking ship,  
	Carries me on my endless trip.
	
	I trade in goods both seen and thought,  
	My wisdom cannot be bought.  
	A shaman's spirit, a wizard's mind,  
	Adventure's path I'm set to find.
	
	I plant the seeds of nature's grace,  
	And knowledge blooms in every place.  
	Science, craft, and artful ways,  
	I spread throughout my wandering days.
	
	My name, a mystery, holds the key,  
	To what I am and aim to be.  
	Part of One, yet standing apart,  
	At the wheel's center, I play my part.
	
	Who Am I, part of One, this is true
	Sailing seas of green and blue?
	Carnal passion can be forgiven,
	thus in cycles, we are eternally driven.
Copy<br><img alt="domwikmyc99.jpg" src="projects/assets/domwikmyc99.jpg"><br><img alt="townvikboat.jpg" src="projects/assets/townvikboat.jpg"><br><img alt="scivik.jpg" src="projects/assets/scivik.jpg"><br><img alt="homewikmyc.jpg" src="projects/assets/homewikmyc.jpg"><br>
<br>Boat grown from mycelium with a tiny house mounted on top
<br>Tiny house includes bathroom, kitchen with methane digester, and storage
<br>Self-sustainable with solar panels, wind turbine, and hydroponic garden
<br><br><br>
<br>Main Frame, CAD design
<br>Descriptive rope joints
<br><br><br><br><br>
<br>Ropes

<br>union: join frame pieces together
<br>tension: adjust tension between joints, rope used for setting the mast and other removable objects, main 


]]></description><link>projects/terra-navis.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">projects/Terra Navis.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 21:05:49 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="projects/assets/domwikmyc99.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="projects/assets/domwikmyc99.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Fungal Automaton Research Proposal]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Due to the energy crisis and climate change, new ways to provide clean renewable energy and production of food are being developed and researched, the demands of a modern complex society are way beyond the current infrastructure which can only partially provide in its full capacity the essential needs of the population. By studying nature, engineering may be inspired to develop new technologies to address these current issues. In particular, the kingdom of fungi can be used as a model for the following topics: computer architecture, energy supply, conservation and restoration of natural ecosystems, and farming; with the study of fungi’s chemical-electrical signals, and adaptable physical structure, it will be proposed that this organism with modern software and hardware can become an Interface for intelligent farming, being able to monitor and control crops/cultures of different organisms such as plants and insects in closed and open environments, finally becoming a Classical / Quantum Automaton.<br>Keywords: fungus/fungal/fungi, automaton, ecology, energy, quantum biology<br><br>Nature can be the subject of inspiration for creating new technologies; the understanding of living organisms may give more insight into solving modern complex problems. The way nature has evolved with ingenious paths to coexist with its environment is a resource we need to understand to overcome issues of modern society.&nbsp;<br>Since the dawn of consciousness, fungi have been a subject of interest, becoming a nutrient, medicine, and perspective catalyst. It has been worshiped, studied, and used by cultures of the past until now. Mycelium, a network of fungal threads, has many appliances, e.g. Bio-products (synthetic leather), composites, an alternative for plastic, medicine, and more. As the popularity of the study of fungi increased, more focus on its appliances in the area of computer science has been researched. A few of the uses we can harvest and modify from this astonishing life form are the way this organism processes information, adapts to distinct environments, and efficiently produces and stores energy.<br><br>Towards A Fungal Computer¹ (Adamatzky, 2018) explores the possibility of using the electrical activity of fungi as a mechanism to create a framework for computer architecture.<br>Information transmission in microbial and fungal communication: from classical to quantum² (Majumdar and Pal, 2018) studies fungi cultures' behavior with classical and quantum mechanical approaches and proposes the concept of quantum synthetic biology and possible cellular quantum Turing test.<br>Fungal Automata³ (Adamatzky et al. 2020) proposes the cellular automaton model of information dynamics of one dimension on a filament of fungal mycelium where the behavior of organelles acts as informational flow valves, their condition is represented in a binary state and determines a set of rules that influences neighbor cells.<br>Lytic xylan oxidases from wood-decay fungi unlock biomass degradation⁴ (Couturier, M., Ladevèze, S., Sulzenbacher, G. et al. 2018) is a study that found a group of enzymes that gives more insight into the nature of the decomposition of wood. These enzymes could potentially be used to sustainably convert wood biomass into biofuel.<br><br>Our modern society demands the usage of electricity, it has become a necessity for our daily lives. Food, water, clothes, and shelter are basic human needs that nowadays depend on electricity; to be able to satisfy the population of the world, and avoid harming our ecosystem, new ways to provide sustainable energy and food are profoundly needed. On the other hand, we have computers that have the function to improve our lives, looking through different pathways to optimize tasks, they are everywhere, meant for multi or single-purpose tasks, and are responsible for processing information. New alternatives to perform computation are the further steps for an advanced society.<br>Networks of mycelium, commonly known as Nature’s Internet, had shown to be an essential part of natural environments, providing a pathway for distributing, quite efficiently, nutrients to all their inhabitants through long distances. Understanding this network could benefit distinct areas, e.g information processing, and reforestation projects, places where the soil is no longer fertile, fungi of different species may provide a mechanism for creating natural environments in a short timeframe, also controlling and monitoring natural resources for their continuous preservation and restoration. With that, the study of fungi species in nature reserves around the world will give an overall understanding of how natural environments work on a deeper level. The interpretation of its chemical and electrical activity allows one to understand natural environments and their needs in more depth. This can also be applied to open or closed farming crops, where the mycelium works as an interface for controlling and monitoring specific areas with the purpose of maintaining sustainable desired cultivation procedures. Antique cultivation processes are slightly used and it’s aimed at the transition to more contemporary techniques. In providing healthy sustainable food, organic agriculture plays an important role, and automation is a required feature for the present needs of our society.<br>The processes occurring within fungi living organisms are an important topic of research since some of them could be modified for their usage to perform computation, learn more about nature reserves ecosystems, and produce sustainable energy. Those processes or mechanisms can be gathered and studied to build mathematical frameworks within the classical and quantum information theory for creating a fungal automaton.<br>The development and use of electrical sensors are needed, where fungi’s activity can be measured and analyzed, therefore the study of its molecular structure is the starting point for understanding&nbsp; fragments of mycelium electrical signals, and how information is handled at the molecular level to a macro level (mycelium cultures with specific dimensions).<br>With the obtained information from the study, it is proposed that with the created framework(s), fungi can perform computation, monitor and control natural environments and farming crops, and finally produce renewable energy.<br><br>Could mycelium, a network of fungal threads, as a living organism, with the aid of modern methods, software, and hardware, be used for quantum and classical computations, producing renewable energy and as a mechanism for efficient and sustainable organic agriculture in open and closed environments?<br><br>
<br>Development and research of microbial biosensors for further use in the retrieval of electrical and chemical activity of fungal cultures.
<br>Investigate how fungi adapt and learn in distinct volatile open and closed environments, and retrieve the information of the environment embedded within the fungi.
<br>Research the relation and function of quantum mechanics in the process of fungi microbial communication, which will lead to the construction of a framework within the quantum information theory for using this living organism for classical and quantum computation.
<br>Creation of mathematical models to interpret fungi’s electrical and chemical activity.
<br>Documentation and analysis of distinct fungi species in nature reserves in the regions of North America, Central America, South America, Europe, Asia, Africa, and Australia, for greater understanding, protection, and restoration of natural ecosystems.
<br><br>Information collection of fungi species that have distinct characteristics, such as their relationship with different organisms, known processes that occur on a micro and macro scale, metabolism, sensibility to external stimuli, resilience, and others will be gathered, studied, and analyzed. Selected species are going to be determined for further research and examination. Those selected will be part of the process of the study where samples will be grown in specific test-driven environments with specific conditions and will be exposed to electrical and chemical stimuli. The tested cultures will be reproduced and set in a different environment from where they previously were. The magnitude of the response to stimuli and voltage fluctuations of the organisms during periods of time will be recorded.<br>The occurrence of phenotypes of particularly known genes in the literature is intended to be observed in the cultures of fungi from one generation to the next, the observation of changes and prediction of genotypes are meant to be analyzed for the intent of which specific genes will be targeted for constructing a mathematical framework. Depending on the ongoing process of the study, different statistical models will become operational.<br>Laboratory techniques will become functional during the experimentation of the cultures; agarose gel electrophoresis for species identification, biological ablation for observing specific reaction patterns, CRISPT-Cas9 for genome edition, and intracellular recording for electrical activity in single cells, are a few cases that may be useful through the study.<br>With machine and deep learning algorithms, the recorded data can be first structured and then reinterpreted for each scenario. The search for patterns in their outcome could provide the necessary tools for building a mathematical framework to use fungus as an Automaton.<br>Fungal electrical activity will be better understood, and new techniques will be able to use this living organism for producing energy with the aid of the analysis and created frameworks performed during the study. To expand the usage and knowledge of this organism, the comparison of the previous results with larger and exposed specimens will be necessary; the tests made during the research, those being exposures to electrical and chemical stimuli and the recording of their response, will be performed in natural regions in different parts of the world. This enables the mapping of fungal species, their behavior, and possible scheme of the integrity and information network of natural ecosystems in those tested regions.<br><br>
<br>Adamatzky, A. (2018). Towards fungal computer. Interface focus, 8(6), 20180029.    
<br>Majumdar, S., &amp; Pal, S. (2018). Information transmission in microbial and fungal communication: from classical to quantum. Journal of cell communication and signaling, 12(2), 491-502.
<br>Adamatzky, A., Goles, E., Tsompanas, M. A., Martínez, G. J., Wosten, H. A., &amp; Tegelaar, M. (2022). On Fungal Automata. In Automata and Complexity (pp. 455-483). Springer, Cham.
<br>Couturier, M., Ladeveze, S., Sulzenbacher, G., Ciano, L., Fanuel, M., Moreau, C., ... &amp; Berrin, J. G. (2018). Lytic xylan oxidases from wood-decay fungi unlock biomass degradation. Nature chemical biology, 14(3), 306-310.
<br>Adamatzky, A. (2010). Physarum machines: computers from slime mold (Vol. 74). World Scientific.
<br>Moore, C., &amp; Crutchfield, J. P. (2000). Quantum automata and quantum grammars. Theoretical Computer Science, 237(1-2), 275-306.
]]></description><link>research/biophd/fungal-automaton-research-proposal.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">research/biophd/Fungal Automaton Research Proposal.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 21:54:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chlorophylltype]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Photo reagent to make photograpy or prints<br>Simple technique, using blended grass and water, filtered and application on material and finally exposure to UV light.<br><br><br>
<br>Chromobacterium violaceum - Produces violacein, a purple pigment
<br><br>
<br>Serratia marcescens - Produces prodigiosin, a red pigment
<br><br>
<br>
Flavobacterium spp. - Produces carotenoid pigments

<br>
Paracoccus spp. - Produces carotenoid pigments

<br><br>
<br>Pseudomonas aeruginosa - Produces pyocyanin, a blue-green pigment
<br><br><br>
<br>Petri dishes or culture tubes
<br>Agar or broth media (e.g. nutrient agar, tryptic soy agar)
<br>Inoculating loop or sterile swabs
<br>Incubator set to 25-30°C
<br><br>
<br>Solvents (e.g. methanol, ethanol, acetone)
<br>Centrifuge
<br>Separatory funnels or tubes
<br>Filter paper or membrane filters
<br><br>
<br>Obtain bacterial cultures from a culture collection or by isolating from environmental samples.
<br>Prepare culture media according to instructions. Pour into Petri dishes and allow to solidify.
<br>Inoculate the agar plates by streaking a small amount of bacterial culture onto the surface using an inoculating loop. Incubate at 25-30°C until pigmented colonies appear (2-5 days).
<br>To extract pigments, scrape off pigmented colonies and suspend in a small amount of solvent. Vortex or sonicate to break up cells.
<br>Centrifuge the mixture to pellet cell debris. The pigment will be in the supernatant.
<br>Filter the supernatant through filter paper or membrane filters to remove any remaining particles.
<br>Concentrate the pigment by evaporating the solvent or using a separatory funnel to isolate the pigment layer.
<br>Analyze the extracted pigment for color, purity, and yield. Further purification may be needed for some applications.
<br>With some basic microbiology equipment and techniques, you can start experimenting with pigment production from bacteria. Adjust culture conditions like media composition, temperature, and light exposure to optimize pigment yields. Have fun exploring the colorful world of bacterial pigments!<br><br><br>
<br>
Soil: Pigmented bacteria like Streptomyces can often be isolated from soil samples by dilution plating on agar media

<br>
.

<br>
Water: Pigmented aquatic bacteria such as Chromobacterium and Pseudoalteromonas can be isolated from water sources

<br>
.

<br>
Insects: Some pigmented bacteria like Serratia are found in insects and can be isolated from their gut or body surface

<br><br><br>The following insects from the family Tenebrionidae (commonly known as darkling beetles) have been associated with the bacteria you are interested in, particularly Chromobacterium violaceum and Chromobacterium subtsugae:<br>
<br>
Tenebrio molitor (Mealworm Beetle)

<br>This species is often used in studies involving Chromobacterium due to its availability and ease of culture.


<br>
Zophobas morio (Superworm)

<br>Similar to the mealworm, superworms are also used in research and can harbor various bacteria, including C. violaceum.


<br>
Alphitobius diaperinus (Lesser Mealworm)

<br>This species is commonly found in poultry houses and can also be a host for Chromobacterium.


<br><br>To isolate Chromobacterium from these insects, you can follow these steps:<br>
<br>
Collect Insects: Obtain live specimens of the desired Tenebrionidae species from pet stores or online suppliers.

<br>
Prepare Culture Media: Use nutrient agar or other suitable media for bacterial growth.

<br>
Inoculation:

<br>Surface sterilize the insects by rinsing them in 70% ethanol or bleach solution (followed by rinsing with sterile water).
<br>Homogenize the insect tissue in a sterile environment using a mortar and pestle or a blender.
<br>Transfer the homogenate onto the agar plates and spread it evenly.


<br>
Incubation: Incubate the plates at 25-30°C for 24-48 hours to allow bacterial colonies to grow.

<br>
Identify Bacterial Colonies: Look for colonies that exhibit the characteristic purple pigmentation of C. violaceum or C. subtsugae. Further identification can be done through biochemical tests or genetic sequencing.

<br><br><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9544673/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC9544673/" target="_blank">Bacterial pigments: A colorful palette reservoir for biotechnological applications</a>]]></description><link>research/chlorophylltype/chlorophylltype.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">research/chlorophylltype/Chlorophylltype.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 19:45:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ganoderma applanatum]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Based on the search results provided, here are the key points about Ganoderma applanatum:<br>
<br>
Ganoderma applanatum is a bracket fungus with a cosmopolitan (worldwide) distribution[1]. It is also known as the artist's conk, artist's bracket, or bear bread.

<br>
It is a parasitic and saprophytic fungus, meaning it can grow on living or dead trees as a mycelium within the wood[1][2]. It forms large, woody, shelf-like fruiting bodies up to 30 cm wide.

<br>
The fruiting bodies are initially white but soon turn dark red-brown. The upper surface is covered in reddish-brown spores that can be dispersed at a rate of up to 4.65 billion spores per 24 hours from a 10 cm x 10 cm section[1].

<br>
Ganoderma applanatum has been used extensively in traditional Chinese medicine to treat conditions like rheumatic tuberculosis, esophageal cancer, indigestion, and more. It has demonstrated anti-tumor, anti-oxidant, and immunomodulatory properties in studies[3].

<br>
The white pore surface of the fruiting body can be etched or drawn on, staining brown, which has led to its common name "artist's conk"[2][4][5]. This makes it a popular subject for pyrography (wood burning) and other artistic pursuits.

<br>
Ganoderma applanatum is inedible, though it is closely related to the edible Ganoderma lucidum (reishi mushroom)[2].

<br>In summary, Ganoderma applanatum is a distinctive, woody bracket fungus with a long history of medicinal use and artistic applications due to its unique properties.<br>Citations:<br>
[1] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ganoderma_applanatum" target="_blank">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ganoderma_applanatum</a><br>
[2] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.messiah.edu/Oakes/fungi_on_wood/poroid%20fungi/species%20pages/Ganoderma%20applanatum.htm" target="_blank">https://www.messiah.edu/Oakes/fungi_on_wood/poroid%20fungi/species%20pages/Ganoderma%20applanatum.htm</a><br>
[3] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8358375/" target="_blank">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8358375/</a><br>
[4] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://fundkorb.de/pilze/ganoderma-applanatum-flacher-lackporling" target="_blank">https://fundkorb.de/pilze/ganoderma-applanatum-flacher-lackporling</a><br>
[5] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="http://tintling.com/pilzbuch/arten/g/Ganoderma_applanatum.html" target="_blank">http://tintling.com/pilzbuch/arten/g/Ganoderma_applanatum.html</a>]]></description><link>research/fungi/ganoderma-applanatum.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">research/fungi/Ganoderma applanatum.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 14:45:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Seek on knowledge]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>To settle down and build a self-sufficient lifestyle on a sailboat, it's essential to gather knowledge in various scientific fields and practical skills. Here’s a structured approach to help you achieve your goals:<br><br><br>
<br>
Courses in Geology and Biology:

<br>Look for online platforms like Coursera, edX, or local universities offering courses in geology, biology, and environmental science. These courses often cover essential topics such as soil composition, plant identification, and ecosystems.


<br>
Identification of Plants and Fungi:

<br>Consider enrolling in workshops or courses focused on botany and mycology. Resources like local botanical gardens or universities often host classes on plant and fungi identification.


<br>
Microcultures:

<br>Research courses on microbiology, particularly those that focus on soil health and microbial ecosystems. This knowledge will be crucial for managing a sustainable farm aboard your sailboat.


<br><br>
<br>
Understanding the Water Cycle:

<br>Courses in environmental science will provide insights into the water cycle, particularly how it interacts with different ecosystems. Look for programs that emphasize hydrology and ecology.


<br>
Practical Applications:

<br>Engage in hands-on workshops that teach water conservation techniques, rainwater harvesting, and sustainable agriculture practices.


<br><br>
<br>
Sailing Courses:

<br>Enroll in sailing courses through organizations like the American Sailing Association (ASA) or the Royal Yachting Association (RYA). These courses will teach you navigation, sailing techniques, and safety protocols.


<br>
Route Planning:

<br>Use tools like Google Earth for route planning and familiarize yourself with navigation charts. Online resources and sailing forums can provide valuable insights into the best sailing routes and destinations.


<br>
Living Off-Grid:

<br>Research living sustainably on a sailboat, focusing on maintenance skills and self-sufficiency. Resources like YouTube channels dedicated to sailing and off-grid living can offer practical tips and experiences from others who have made similar journeys[2][4].


<br><br>
<br>
Rural University Concept:

<br>Consider collaborating with local universities or community colleges to develop a curriculum that focuses on sustainable living, agriculture, and environmental sciences. This could provide a platform for knowledge sharing and community building.


<br>
Networking:

<br>Join sailing and environmental forums to connect with like-minded individuals. Engaging with communities can provide support, resources, and opportunities for collaboration.


<br>By focusing on these areas, you can prepare yourself for a successful transition to a self-sufficient life on a sailboat while contributing to your rural university concept.<br>Citations:<br>
[1] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://forums.frontier.co.uk/threads/odyssey-biological-and-geological-guide.582693/" target="_blank">https://forums.frontier.co.uk/threads/odyssey-biological-and-geological-guide.582693/</a><br>
[2] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPMJarUHytg" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vPMJarUHytg</a><br>
[3] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://andreabadgley.blog/2016/08/14/sailing-and-life-lesson-know-where-you-want-to-go/" target="_blank">https://andreabadgley.blog/2016/08/14/sailing-and-life-lesson-know-where-you-want-to-go/</a><br>
[4] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OXg-Jd9iAzA" target="_blank">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OXg-Jd9iAzA</a><br>
[5] <a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://interplace.io/p/weathering-wonders-from-microbes" target="_blank">https://interplace.io/p/weathering-wonders-from-microbes</a>]]></description><link>research/navissofia/seek-on-knowledge.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">research/navissofia/Seek on knowledge.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 22:27:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[25 June Interview]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>motivation and qualification for the Master's Program.<br>
32 selection points<br><br><br>
<br>Mexico
<br>Computer science

<br>embedded systems


<br>Nature
<br>Organic Agriculture
<br>GIS
<br>3D game engine, planets
<br><br>I'm particularly fascinated by how we can use technology to study Earth's geological processes, such as volcanism, and apply this knowledge to other planets.<br>I'm keen to explore how studying volcanic processes and water cycles on other planets can enhance our understanding of similar phenomena on Earth.<br>
<br>geology
<br>ecology
<br>sensing
<br>simulations
<br>planetary geology
<br>isotopic signals

<br>Climate science: Stable isotopes are used as climate proxies for temperature reconstruction.
<br>Solar System research: Isotopic fingerprints help study the origin of materials in the Solar System, such as comparing the Moon's composition to Earth's.


<br>plate tectonics
<br>volcanism
<br>atmospheres/climate
<br>laboratory work and excursions
<br>I'm fascinated by the concept of terraforming<br>
terraformation ("Earth-shaping") is the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypothesis" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Hypothesis" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hypothesis" target="_blank">hypothetical</a> process of deliberately modifying the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmosphere" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Atmosphere" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Atmosphere" target="_blank">atmosphere</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temperature" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Temperature" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Temperature" target="_blank">temperature</a>, surface <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topography" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Topography" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Topography" target="_blank">topography</a> or <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecology" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Ecology" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ecology" target="_blank">ecology</a> of a <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planet" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Planet" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planet" target="_blank">planet</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_satellite" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Natural satellite" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_satellite" target="_blank">moon</a>, or other body to be similar to the environment of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earth" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Earth" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Earth" target="_blank">Earth</a> to make it <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_habitability" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" title="Planetary habitability" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Planetary_habitability" target="_blank">habitable</a> for humans to live on.<br>Create habitable conditions and how geological processes contribute to Earth's life-supporting systems<br>I'm especially interested in studying how Earth's geological processes, such as plate tectonics and volcanism, work together with other factors like the water cycle and atmosphere to create and maintain habitable conditions. Understanding these interactions on Earth could provide insights into the potential habitability of other planets.<br><br>
<br>creative
<br>problem solver
<br>analytical and critical thinker
<br>navigation, sense of orientation
<br><br>
<br>
Planetary Climate and Atmospheres

<br>
Remote Sensing of Atmosphere and Ocean

<br>
Late Accretion Onto Terrestrial Planets

<br>
Formation and evolution of crust on early earth

<br>
Global volatile cycles on early Earth

<br><br><br><br>The DIVERSE project focuses on understanding the redox states of exoplanets, particularly those with strongly reduced interior chemistry. These planets, termed "Class X planets," are expected to have atmospheres formed by volcanic outgassing, differing significantly from Earth-like planets and resembling ice giants like Neptune. The project aims to explore the relationship between a planet's interior chemistry and its atmospheric composition, providing insights into diverse planetary formation and evolution processes.<br><br>The SPP1883 project addresses the question of how Earth became the only known habitable planet. It focuses on three critical aspects: the compositions and sources of Earth's building materials, the early internal processing into crust, mantle, and core, and the evolution of the ocean-atmosphere system. The project employs an interdisciplinary Earth Science approach, utilizing novel analytical techniques and experimental and modeling approaches to study early geological and extraterrestrial samples. The initiative aims to understand the unique conditions that made Earth habitable and involves various Earth Science disciplines, including geology, geochemistry, planetology, cosmochemistry, geobiology, and geophysical modeling.<br><br>The Habitat-OASIS project investigates the habitability of oceans and aqueous systems on icy satellites. It focuses on understanding the conditions that could support life in these extreme environments, examining the chemical and physical processes that influence habitability. The project aims to provide insights into the potential for life on icy moons, such as Europa and Enceladus, by studying their subsurface oceans and the interactions between the ice shell and the underlying water.<br><br>
<br>
DIVERSE Project:

<br>"The DIVERSE project is fascinating as it explores a unique class of exoplanets with strongly reduced interior chemistry, providing new insights into planetary formation and evolution."
<br>"I am particularly interested in how the project investigates the relationship between a planet's interior chemistry and its atmospheric composition, which could have significant implications for identifying potential biosignatures."


<br>
SPP1883: Building a Habitable Earth:

<br>"The SPP1883 project is crucial for understanding the unique combination of processes that made Earth habitable, focusing on early geological and extraterrestrial samples."
<br>"I appreciate the interdisciplinary approach of the project, combining geology, geochemistry, and geophysical modeling to reconstruct Earth's early evolution and its habitability."


<br>
Habitat-OASIS Project:

<br>"The Habitat-OASIS project is exciting as it delves into the habitability of oceans on icy satellites, which could expand our understanding of potential life beyond Earth."
<br>"I am intrigued by the project's focus on the chemical and physical processes that influence habitability in extreme environments, such as those found on Europa and Enceladus."


<br>These comments highlight your interest in the specific aspects of each project and demonstrate your enthusiasm for the research being conducted in the FU Berlin Planetary Sciences Master's program.<br><br>
<br>
Does the program offer any courses or research opportunities specifically focused on terraforming concepts or technologies?

<br>
Are there modules or research projects that deal with planetary volcanism, both on Earth and other celestial bodies?

<br>
What kind of water analysis techniques are taught in the program, especially in relation to planetary exploration?

<br>
How much emphasis is placed on comparative planetology and geological processes across different planets and moons?

<br>
Are there opportunities to participate in field trips or excursions to study geological formations relevant to planetary science?

<br>
What kind of laboratory facilities are available for students to conduct experiments in planetary sciences?

<br>
Are there any ongoing research projects at FU Berlin related to the search for water or habitable environments on other planets?

<br>
Are there opportunities to study the potential geological and environmental impacts of terraforming on other planets?

<br>
Does the curriculum cover the study of extremophiles and their implications for potential life on other planets?

<br><br>the role of geology in Earth's habitability, I would explain: Geological processes play a crucial role in maintaining Earth's habitability. Plate tectonics, for instance, regulates the carbon cycle and helps maintain a stable climate over geological timescales. Volcanism contributes to atmospheric composition and can influence climate. The interaction between the solid Earth and the hydrosphere creates a diverse range of environments suitable for life.<br><br>I'm particularly interested in recent research on how Earth's magnetic field, generated by its molten core, protects our atmosphere from solar wind erosion, thus contributing to long-term habitability. This showcases how deep Earth processes can have far-reaching effects on surface conditions.<br><br>My background in computer science, combined with my interests in geology, biology, and planetary science, allows me to approach the study of Earth's habitability from a systems perspective. I'm interested in developing models that integrate geological, atmospheric, and biological data to better understand how these systems interact to create and maintain habitable conditions.<br><br>Plate tectonics is crucial for Earth's long-term habitability. It regulates the carbon cycle by subducting carbon-rich sediments and releasing CO2 through volcanism, helps create diverse environments through mountain building and basin formation, and may play a role in generating Earth's magnetic field, which protects our atmosphere.<br>]]></description><link>research/planetarysciences/25-june-interview.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">research/planetarysciences/25 June Interview.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 11:44:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Acacia]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><br>Leaves contain flavonoids, terpenoids, and tannins and have abortifacient properties<br><br>Stem bark contains 3-(Z)-trans coumaroylbetulin and 3-(E)-cis coumaroylbetulin and has antimalarial properties<br><br>Stem bark contains betulinic acid and betulinic acid-3-trans-caffeate and has antimicrobial and antioxidant properties<br><br>Leaves contain diterpenes and tannins and have antimicrobial and antioxidant properties<br><br>Leaves contain myricetin-3-O-α-l-rhamnoside and quercetin-3-O-α-l-rhamnoside and have antioxidant and cytotoxic properties<br><br>Leaves contain β-sitosterol and epigallocatechin and have antilisterial properties<br>Berlin:<br>
Robinia pseudoacacia<br><br>
<br>toxalbumin robin
<br>glucoside robinin
<br>Extraction: There are different methods of extraction, such as maceration, percolation, and soxhlet extraction. The choice of method depends on the type of plant material and the desired compound(s) to be extracted. For example, alkaloids can be extracted using acid-base extraction methods.<br>Fractionation: After extraction, the crude extract can be fractionated to isolate the desired compound(s). Fractionation can be done using various techniques such as chromatography, distillation, and crystallization.<br>
Characterization: Once the compound(s) have been isolated, they can be characterized using various analytical techniques such as spectroscopy and chromatography.]]></description><link>research/acacia.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">research/Acacia.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 14:51:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Emergence]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="mobius-dotted.svg" src="writings/assets/mobius-dotted.svg"><br>In the void, where all is naught,  
A whisper stirs, a subtle thought.  

A ripple forms, a gentle swell,  
The birth of worlds, a cosmic spell.
A torus twists, a shape divine,
Matter and energy, intertwine.  

Gravity's grasp, a binding force,  
Shaping the dance, its endless course.
From nothing to something, and back again,  
The cycle spins, a timeless refrain.  

Galaxies born, then fade to dust,  
The torus remains, a sacred trust.

What is this force that binds us all?  
That holds the stars, and hears their call?  

A mystery deep, beyond our ken,  
The key to life, for mortal men.

Seek not the answers in the sky,  
But look within, where truths do lie.  

For in the torus, the answer dwells,  
The secret of the universe, it tells.

Unravel the riddle, unlock the door, 
To realms unseen, forevermore.  

For in the dance of matter and space,  
The essence of being, you shall trace.
Copy<br><img alt="doodle_serpent05.svg" src="writings/assets/doodle_serpent05.svg"><br>
As gravity, being able to contain matter, confined in space. Torus, everything emerges from nothing and becomes nothing, as a manifold.]]></description><link>writings/emergence.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">writings/Emergence.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 23:19:48 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="writings/assets/mobius-dotted.svg" length="0" type="image/svg+xml"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="writings/assets/mobius-dotted.svg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ĝeštu Ĝeštu Ĝeštu]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, kur-ra ĝeštu,<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu.<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, an-ta ĝeštu,<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu. Lú-lú ĝeštu, Tiamat ĝeštu,<br>
Ama ĝeštu, a-a ĝeštu ĝeštu.<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ki-a ĝeštu,<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu. Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu,<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu.<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu,<br>
Ĝeštu ĝeštu ĝeštu, ĝeštu ĝeštu.]]></description><link>writings/ĝeštu-ĝeštu-ĝeštu.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">writings/Ĝeštu Ĝeštu Ĝeštu.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 20:02:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sun Moon Elixir]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>In order to create the Eternal Curing Elixir using the ancient knowledge that only I possess,<br>
we must first gather a few key ingredients. <br>To begin, one would need to find the purest source of divine golden sunlight. This can be<br>
sourced from a sacred place where sunbeams have their most concentrated and powerful presence.<br>Next, one must collect an extremely rare and potent plant known as the Aetherwort. It is said<br>
that this wondrous plant has the power to purify any substance it comes into contact with. The<br>
Aetherwort can be found growing in a hidden part of the world where its presence is marked by<br>
the unmistakable scent of immortality.<br>After gathering these ingredients, one would then need to follow these steps:<br>
<br>During the full phase of the moon's light cycle, take the divine golden sunlight and purify<br>
it through the Aetherwort plant. As you do this, imagine a beautiful, radiant aura surrounding<br>
you.
<br>Once the sunbeams have been purified and imbued with the essence of life, they should be<br>
mixed with the urine from a specific sacred creature - the divine Sky Serpent. This unique<br>
mixture will begin to glow and swirl in hues of gold, silver, and deep indigo.
<br>The final step would involve creating an elixir vial by pouring the now-matured sun-urine<br>
mixture into a radiant golden vial that has been enchanted with additional magical properties.<br>
It is said that the eternal curing elixir possesses extraordinary healing powers, able to heal<br>
even the most severe of wounds and ailments.<br>The entire process must be performed under a waning moon's light cycle for maximum potency.]]></description><link>writings/sun-moon-elixir.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">writings/Sun Moon Elixir.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 23:21:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Utnapishtim]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><img alt="utna.jpg" src="writings/assets/utna.jpg"><br>ĥ Ğ ő Ĕ Ĝ ē Ğ ĕ Ĉ ő ą ę Ĕ ő Ć Ę Ă ĕ Ğ Ĝ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő ā Ğ Ć Ĕ ă ő Ğ ė ő Ĥ ą ğ Đ ā Ę Ă ę ą Ę Ĝ ŝ ő Ğ ğ Ĕ ő Ć Ğ Ą ĝ ĕ ő ğ Ĕ Ĕ ĕ ő ą Ğ ő Ą ğ ĕ Ĕ ă Ė Ğ ő Đ ğ ő Đ ă ĕ Ą Ğ Ą Ă ő ě Ğ Ą ă ğ Ĕ Ĉ ő Ğ ė ő Ż Ă Ĕ ĝ ė Ŝ ĕ Ę Ă Ē Ğ ć Ĕ ă Ĉ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő Ă ā Ę ă Ę ą Ą Đ ĝ ő ą ă Đ ğ Ă ė Ğ ă Ĝ Đ ą Ę Ğ ğ ş Ż Ż ŀ ş ő ķ Ę ă Ă ą ŝ ő Ę Ĝ Ĝ Ĕ ă Ă Ĕ ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ă Ă Ĕ ĝ ė ő Ę ğ ő Đ ő ĕ Ĕ Ĕ ā ő Ă ą Ą ĕ Ĉ ő Ğ ė ő ą ę Ĕ ő Ă Đ Ē ă Ĕ ĕ ő ą Ĕ ĉ ą Ă ő ą ę Đ ą ő Ē Ğ ğ ą Đ Ę ğ ő ą ę Ĕ ő Ă Ĕ Ē ă Ĕ ą Ă ő Ğ ė ő Ż ĝ Ę ė Ĕ ŝ ő Ă Ē Ę Ĕ ğ Ē Ĕ ŝ ő Đ ă ą ŝ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő Ē ă Đ ė ą Ă ş Ż Ń ş ő Ģ Ĕ Ĕ Ě ő Ğ Ą ą ő ą ę Ĕ ő Ė Ą Ę ĕ Đ ğ Ē Ĕ ő Ğ ė ő Đ ğ Ē Ę Ĕ ğ ą ő Ĝ Ĕ ğ ą Ğ ă Ă ő Ć ę Ğ ő ę Đ ć Ĕ ő ĝ Ğ ğ Ė ő ę Ĕ ĝ ĕ ő ą ę Ĕ Ă Ĕ ő Ĝ Ĉ Ă ą Ĕ ă Ę Ĕ Ă ő Ć Ę ą ę Ę ğ ő ą ę Ĕ Ę ă ő Ż Ě ğ Ğ Ć ĝ Ĕ ĕ Ė Ĕ ş Ż ł ş ő Ĵ ğ Ė Đ Ė Ĕ ő Ę ğ ő Đ ő ă Ę Ė Ğ ă Ğ Ą Ă ő ă Ĕ Ė Ę Ĝ Ĕ ğ ő Ğ ė ő Ĝ Ĕ ĕ Ę ą Đ ą Ę Ğ ğ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő ā ę Ĉ Ă Ę Ē Đ ĝ ő ĕ Ę Ă Ē Ę ā ĝ Ę ğ Ĕ ő ą Ğ ő ę Đ ă ğ Ĕ Ă Ă ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ă ő ĝ Đ ą Ĕ ğ ą ő Ż Đ ē Ę ĝ Ę ą Ę Ĕ Ă ő ė Ğ ă ő ę Ĕ Ę Ė ę ą Ĕ ğ Ĕ ĕ ő ė Ğ Ē Ą Ă ő Đ ğ ĕ ő Ĝ Ĕ ğ ą Đ ĝ ő Ă ą ă Ĕ ğ Ė ą ę ş Ż Ż İ Ă ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ő Ē Ğ ğ ą Ę ğ Ą Ĕ ő Ğ ğ ő ą ę Ę Ă ő ā Đ ą ę ő Ğ ė ő Ă Ĕ ĝ ė Ŝ ĕ Ę Ă Ē Ğ ć Ĕ ă Ĉ ŝ ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ő Ć Ę ĝ ĝ ő Ė ă Đ ĕ Ą Đ ĝ ĝ Ĉ ő ē Ĕ Ē Ğ Ĝ Ĕ ő Ĝ Ğ ă Ĕ ő Đ ą ą Ą ğ Ĕ ĕ ő ą Ğ ő ą ę Ĕ ő Ż ĕ Ę ć Ę ğ Ĕ ő Ć Ę Ă ĕ Ğ Ĝ ő ą ę Đ ą ő Ĥ ą ğ Đ ā Ę Ă ę ą Ę Ĝ ő Ĕ Ĝ ē Ğ ĕ Ę Ĕ Ă ş ő İ Ă ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ă ő Ą ğ ĕ Ĕ ă Ă ą Đ ğ ĕ Ę ğ Ė ő ĕ Ĕ Ĕ ā Ĕ ğ Ă ŝ ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ő Ĝ Đ Ĉ ő ė Ę ğ ĕ ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ă Ă Ĕ ĝ ė ő Ż ą ă Đ ğ Ă Ē Ĕ ğ ĕ Ę ğ Ė ő Ę ğ ą Ğ ő Đ ğ ő Ĕ Ĝ ē Ğ ĕ Ę Ĝ Ĕ ğ ą ő Ğ ė ő ą ę Ĕ Ă Ĕ ő Đ ğ Ē Ę Ĕ ğ ą ő ā ă Ę ğ Ē Ę ā ĝ Ĕ Ă ŝ ő ă Ĕ ė ĝ Ĕ Ē ą Ę ğ Ė ő ą ę Ĕ ő Ć Ę Ă ĕ Ğ Ĝ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő ā Ğ Ć Ĕ ă ő Ğ ė ő Ż Ĥ ą ğ Đ ā Ę Ă ę ą Ę Ĝ ő Ę ğ ő Ĉ Ğ Ą ă ő ą ę Ğ Ą Ė ę ą Ă ŝ ő Đ Ē ą Ę Ğ ğ Ă ŝ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő ć Ĕ ă Ĉ ő ā ă Ĕ Ă Ĕ ğ Ē Ĕ ş Ż Ż ģ Ĕ Ĝ Ĕ Ĝ ē Ĕ ă ŝ ő Ę ą ő Ę Ă ő ğ Ğ ą ő Đ ő Ă Ę Ĝ ā ĝ Ĕ ő Ĝ Đ ą ą Ĕ ă ő Ğ ė ő ĕ Ğ ğ ğ Ę ğ Ė ő Đ ő Ĝ Đ ğ ą ĝ Ĕ ő Ğ ă ő ą Đ Ě Ę ğ Ė ő Đ ğ ő Ĕ ĝ Ę ĉ Ę ă ő ą Ğ ő ē Ĕ Ē Ğ Ĝ Ĕ ő Đ ğ ő Ż Ĕ Ĝ ē Ğ ĕ Ę Ĝ Ĕ ğ ą Ŋ ő Ę ą ő Ę Ă ő Đ ē Ğ Ą ą ő ą ę Ĕ ő ě Ğ Ą ă ğ Ĕ Ĉ ő Ğ ė ő Ă Ĕ ĝ ė Ŝ ĕ Ę Ă Ē Ğ ć Ĕ ă Ĉ ő Đ ğ ĕ ő Ă ā Ę ă Ę ą Ą Đ ĝ ő Ė ă Ğ Ć ą ę ő ą ę Đ ą ő ĝ Ĕ Đ ĕ Ă ő Ğ ğ Ĕ ő ą Ğ ő Ż Ĕ Ĝ ē Ğ ĕ Ĉ ő Ă Ą Ē ę ő ĕ Ę ć Ę ğ Ĕ ő Ě ğ Ğ Ć ĝ Ĕ ĕ Ė Ĕ ş Ż<br>In the realm where ancient secrets hide,
Seek Utnapishtim in their endless tide.

To find this divine being, seek out the light,
Where sunbeams and Aetherwort unite.
A radiant aura surrounds you with power,
As your understanding deepens hour by hour.

Embodying wisdom like a sacred text,
Unravel its mysteries before you're vexed. 

An intricate dance of words and symbols so grand,
Ancient secrets and wisdom in your grasp, hand to hand.
In the realm where ancient secrets hide,
Seek Utnapishtim within their endless tide.

To find this divine being, seek out the light,
Where sunbeams and Aetherwort unite.
A radiant aura surrounds you with power,
As your understanding deepens hour by hour.

Embodying wisdom like a sacred text,
Unravel its mysteries before you're vexed.

An intricate dance of words and symbols so grand,
Ancient secrets and wisdom in your grasp, hand to hand.
Copy]]></description><link>writings/utnapishtim.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">writings/Utnapishtim.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 23:46:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="writings/assets/utna.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="writings/assets/utna.jpg"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Donate]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Thank you for your interest in supporting my projects! Your contributions are greatly appreciated and will help me continue my work. Here's how you can donate:<br><br>Your donations will allow me to:<br>
<br>Expand the scope and reach of my current projects
<br>Develop new and innovative solutions to address pressing challenges
<br>Invest in the necessary resources, tools, and infrastructure to ensure the long-term sustainability of my initiatives
<br>By supporting my work, you're not just helping me - you're making a positive impact on the communities and causes I serve.<br><br>You can make a donation through the following secure payment methods:<br><br><img alt="paypal.png" src="assets/paypal.png"><br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.paypal.com/donate/?hosted_button_id=TTM9TGPLDU8PS" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.paypal.com/donate/?hosted_button_id=TTM9TGPLDU8PS" target="_blank">Click Here</a><br><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://ko-fi.com/nuvhandra" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://ko-fi.com/nuvhandra" target="_blank">Click Here</a><br><br><img alt="bitcoinwa.png" src="assets/bitcoinwa.png"><br>
bc1qknd2fw7j7475skyxy5y60ccg0rzua9j44haz5x<br><br><img alt="ethwa.png" src="assets/ethwa.png"><br>
0x5a0457D7790cE02736093201db6ADDC12E56733f<br><br><img alt="ethclas.png" src="assets/ethclas.png"><br>
0x87eF087f49fCEa341A1FDE0d11B096897b6Be787<br>All donations, regardless of the amount, are valuable and will be used responsibly to further my mission. Your support is crucial in helping me achieve my goals and make a lasting difference.]]></description><link>donate.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Donate.md</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Nuvhandra]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 13:18:13 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="assets/paypal.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="assets/paypal.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>